A challenge?
If you're a man of the Empire,
you must accept!
Ah, but I'm not very good with blades...
How, then, do you intend to protect
the princess you serve?!
Enough, Warrant Officer Deinkun.
Would you mock my knights
in my very presence?
Torway's skill lies in the gun, anyway.
In a modern battlefield—
My deepest apologies, Your Highness!
No...
Please forgive me, Your Highness!
Enough. Raise your head.
Please... I beg you...
Why not try a chess match instead?
That's something Torway's good at.
A splendid proposal.
Engage in a battle of wits on a chessboard
and show us you're the superior soldier.
Of course, Your Highness!
I am honored for this chance at redemption!
That's check, right?
You are a fearsome foe, Torway Remeon!
However, this is not the end!
Just 54 moves? That's terrible.
You're in the way! Move!
S-Solork!
W-Water...
The Northern Katjvarna Rebellion
I'm alive...
Back to yourself now?
"My bad, I forgot to come get you yesterday."
First Lieutenant Sazaluf, you asshole!
It's your own fault.
If you've come back to your senses,
then get off the princess's lap.
Solork, do you have anything to say to me?
Let me see...
If I had to rest on someone's lap,
I'd prefer they had a little
more meat on their bones.
A woman—
You can just lie there and die!
Well, come back to life soon.
You're being a bother.
You're the best, Yatori!
Yatori-san, did you save those for Ikta-san?
I saved them to eat for myself. That's all.
The guys on horses are so lucky...
Escorting a supply train must be quite
boring to you, Warrant Officer Yatorishino.
No, I'm well aware of
the importance of this mission.
I'm more surprised, Major,
that a high-level officer
like yourself is coming along.
There's a reason I have to.
Building a base places a rather
heavy burden on the locals,
so we need to keep them happy.
Are you disappointed?
That's what a military is
supposed to be, right?
War exists to uphold the peace.
You shouldn't destroy the peace
to support a war.
You may well be right.
W-We're finally here.
Are we there yet?
Ikkun-dono!
No yelling!
Anyway, hello, Kanna!
Your hair's so charming in that ribbon.
You were in there the whole time?
No wonder it was heavy—
That is incorrect!
I was sleeping in that wagon,
and you started pushing it without
even asking my permission.
You're lying.
When you got out, you said,
"Are we there yet?"
Perhaps dehydration is
causing you to hear things.
I'm supposed to wait here!
You need to make good use of your time!
It's not every day we get to visit a town.
Who are you?
Hello there, beautiful young lady.
Sorry to bother you, but we're very thirsty.
What a nice lady. She gave us sugarcane
to tide us over until we get to the well.
Ikkun-dono, are you one of
those "lady-killer" types?
That's a misunderstanding.
All the older women in the world
are conspiring to seduce me.
Anyway, she didn't seem
put off by my uniform.
The people here don't seem to
have anything against soldiers.
That's right.
This is an important supply base,
so Major Toakk insists we're careful
about how we interact with the locals.
Not Lieutenant General Safida?
He just puts the Major
in charge of everything.
So, the guy at the top does nothing,
and Major Toakk's in charge
of keeping an eye on him?
There's one exception, though.
Lieutenant General Safida gives orders
personally whenever the Sinack are involved.
The Sinack?
Why?
Well... I think he likes being mean to them.
That's how it seems to me,
watching the way he acts.
So, that's what that was, then...
First Lieutenant...
This isn't something
you're supposed to do, is it?
Spirits can't move without light.
If you tore the spirits away from
the ones they contracted with,
that would go against
the teachings of the Alderans.
This is spirit abuse.
I can tell you this now,
because you've seen it,
but these orders came directly
from Lieutenant General Safida.
These spirits were taken from
the Sinack, aren't they?
You're pretty smart.
I only see wind and fire spirits.
Without these two types,
they're much less effective at fighting.
It's a desperate measure intended
to break the will of the Sinack.
And, well, given how quiet
they've been lately,
it seems to be working.
I wouldn't do things this way.
More than anything,
it's given them a reason to go to war.
Retaking their partners who were
cruelly stolen from them
is a simple, powerful reason.
Ikkun-dono?
What's up?
Can I ask you something?
Sure thing.
By the way, the right half
of my bed is open tonight.
Th-That's not it!
Um, about that book...
Oh, the Great Alafatra Survey Records.
You said the analysis of the Aldera religion
was the most interesting, right?
Yes.
It's quite interesting on its own,
but I had a question about
a more fundamental issue.
A more fundamental issue?
Don't you think it's strange?
The Sinack speak of the spirits without
mentioning God—that is, Alderamin.
But we all say that the four great spirits
were sent to our world by God...
Um...
We say that the spirits come
from Alderamin to begin with.
Th-That's right!
So, from our perspective, it makes no sense.
But the Sinack's spirit religion exists
without any reference to Alderamin.
And then I realized that maybe it was
our beliefs that needed to be questioned.
The spirits never tell us
to believe in God, do they?
You can go now.
You don't get many chances to go into town.
In that case, I'll wait outside.
It looks like I need to order you
to spread your wings and relax.
Of course, that is one of the orders
I have been given.
But these are the only wings
I have to spread.
It's probably her sense of humor that
keeps her from being overbearing.
Even if she was born at the wrong time,
she would still be a splendid soldier.
They're late to come get us today.
Yes.
They might be busy,
but we're not people they would keep waiting.
Excuse me. I'm here as the
commander's representative—
Let's get out of here.
The core tenets of the Aldera religion
involve obeying the commandments.
But the spirit religion of the Sinack
has no such commandments...
So, um...
Kanna, there's no need to rush.
Take your time to find the right words.
Their religion consists of mere gratitude
toward the Four Great spirits,
and a variety of festivals
to show that gratitude.
Their religion has nothing to do
with commandments and rules.
If what the book says is right,
and the Aldera religion and
spirit worship are unrelated,
the spirits' true nature has nothing to do
with being messengers of Alderamin.
Wow, Kanna!
You broke the curse of God!
And nearly on your own!
Th-The curse of God?
The bigotry that twists the truth by
ignoring anything that doesn't benefit God!
Unless you shake off that curse,
Hey!
you'll never be able to pursue
the path of true science!
Ikkun-dono?
For one thing, if there really
was an omnipotent god,
his first commandment would be
"Thou shalt be lazy."
Any god who tells you
something else is a fake!
I didn't go that far...
You're a weird guy, Ikkun.
Major!
Get her!
Fall back!
We've finished what we came here to do.
Leave the rest to me, Major Toakk.
I will hereby pursue the enemy.
What happened?
Five imperial soldiers.
One Sinack man.
And the residents, I guess.
Be careful. The enemy could still be inside.
I'm aware.
Everybody who lived here
is pretty much dead, huh?
What's this?
Ikkun-dono, those are Alderan
pilgrimage clothes...
Looks like.
But why?
The Sinack wouldn't wear these.
You won't get away.
All troops, ready ranged weapons!
Halt the attack!
Everyone stop!
They had an ambush ready.
People of Sinack!
Why did you slay our comrades?
Explain yourselves!
Oh, so it hurts when your friends die?
You hurt, too, huh?!
Why did you steal our Hahashiku?!
Hahashiku?
You have them with you now.
Would anyone but a monster
steal them from us?!
You mean the spirits?
You've made us change a lot
of things to benefit you.
We're forbidden from
selling in the plains town,
you pay us practically nothing
for the millet we grow,
and we can only buy a few
vegetables and fruits.
When a few of us were forced into thievery,
you killed them all!
And then you stole our Hahashiku...
If you're not monsters, then what are you?!
Give me your demands, then.
What do you want from the army now?
There's nothing we want.
We shall return things to
the way they should be.
We'll defeat you, retake the Hahashiku,
and return the world of the Sinack
to how it should be.
We are about to declare a holy war.
I am Nanaku Daru, chieftain of the Sinack,
and in my name I begin the holy war!
They retreated to the Great Alafatra
after their declaration of war.
I see.
So, Toakk is dead?
Don't tell Central about it yet.
But...
We can just send a bigger report later.
There'll be some casualties, either way.
I am interpreting this declaration of war
as involving their entire tribe.
It looks like the time has come
for a great purge.
A holy war...
Yatori, let me double-check.
That's really what they said, right?
Yes, it was.
We can just take them head on!
We need to take revenge for Major Toakk!
The mountain savages think they can take us?
What are you drunks babbling about?!
What sort of knight would get excited
over a fight like this?
What the heck?
You wanted to go to war more than anyone.
Of course.
That is, if our enemy is
the hated land of Kioka.
However, a knight's sword
is not a tool of murder!
I'm a little surprised to see Warrant
Officer Hargunska opposed to the war.
It's rude to say that.
A knight should be reluctant to point
his blade at a fellow imperial citizen.
I think so, too.
It's amazing that Dekkun was able
to speak up in that atmosphere.
A holy war...
A holy war, huh?
You're still thinking about that?
It doesn't exist.
The term "holy war" doesn't exist
in the Sinack language.
What do you mean?
To the Sinack, war is
simply a means of survival.
They consider it neither good nor bad,
and they certainly don't consider it holy.
The only things they call holy
are the Hahashiku,
the Four Great spirits.
Why did you steal our Hahashiku?!
Then, if the reason for their holy war
has to do with the spirits,
they might be calling it that because
they're taking back something holy.
No, I can't see them coming up
with some logic like that.
There's probably only one answer.
Someone's been giving them
ready-made excuses for war.
Thoughts on the Aldera Religion
You should probably get back to your unit.
Yeah.
Next time we meet,
I'll tell you my thoughts on
the Sinack and the spirits.
Listen up!
We'll be leaving on a punitive expedition
against the Sinack at 0600 tomorrow!
Everyone be ready to go!
I'm very disappointed.
The brass thinks that a princess
has no place on the front lines.
We're all very disappointed as well.
You're glad to be rid of me.
At a time when our national energy
is already spent,
it's madness to start
a fight with our own citizens.
When I return, I want to see you all safe.
Yes, Your Highness!
To be honest, I'm a little relieved.
But why send her back halfway, to a base
at the south edge of the Northern region?
It might be that the Lieutenant General
doesn't want to send her back to Central.
Probably.
Given the speed at which he put
together the punitive expedition,
He likely never mentioned it to Central.
He's doing all this on his own.
B-But we're still on reserve standby, right?
Matthew, my friend, I'm afraid that
common-sense arguments only work on
people who have common sense.
All we can do now is pray that the
Lieutenant General is one of those people.
Our unit will now depart on a punitive
expedition against the Sinack!
All troops, be fully ready and stay sharp!
The war's about to begin...
What are you doing here, Ikkun?
These are...
Get used to using them now.
They're our trump card for when we need them.
Advance!
Don't falter!
We can't...
Get our air mortars out, too!
We can't!
Aren't our mortars ready yet?!
Get a hold of yourself!
Ikkun-dono,
there's not a trace of science here.
Don't falter! Advance!
The Northern Katjvarna Rebellion
was a larger battle
than had ever been seen in the north before,
and this is how it began...
Staining a page of the empire's history
with the blood of its own citizens.
Next time: Some Day, for the Third Time...
"Some Day, for the Third Time..."